<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Compiling Leadership</title>
    <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Compiling Leadership</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019 Ned Rockson. Some Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 20:41:27 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.nedrockson.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Agile OR The Agile That Doesn&#39;t Work For Your Team is the Same Agile That Doesn&#39;t Work For Others</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/management/early-agile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 20:41:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/management/early-agile/</guid>
      <description>While researching the history of the standup meeting, I came across Jim Coplien&#39;s 1994 retrospective on development of Borland Quattro Pro for Windows. In it, Jim analyzes a herculean effort where a team of eight developers wrote over 1 million lines of code over a 31 month period, or approximately 1,000 lines of code per week per developer1.
During development the team stumbled across early core agile principles almost a decade before the Agile Manifesto would be published.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: Stoic Joy</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2018/7/stoic-joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 21:18:12 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2018/7/stoic-joy/</guid>
      <description>Seneca reminds us that joy is something to strive for. Something that is not an externally manifested trait but something that cames from within. Something that comes with being content with who we are and what we do. Something that allows us to stay calm and curious in the face of adversity.
These descriptions were never in my description of joy. I saw joy as something that came from within (not something that one easily inspires in another) but still something that manifested in happiness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cost Per Usage</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/per-usage-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 19:00:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/per-usage-cost/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m always surprised when I realize my $400 suit costs about $20 each wear. Of course I may not live similar to a banker who probably wear a suit 50-100 times before replacement, but most formal engagements require me to spend one suit utilization unit and when I start to iron it the thought crosses my mind.
Bike shorts, cost somewhere around $5 whenever I go for a ride. I bought my golf clubs for a steal at $150 and have played at least 50 rounds of golf for a cost of $3 per round.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossing the Chasm</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/books/crossing-the-chasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 12:52:46 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/books/crossing-the-chasm/</guid>
      <description>Absolutely fantastic book. I forgot to write a review for it initially and now (6 months later) I finally am getting back to it. I can say that over the past 6 months, this is the book I&#39;ve referenced the most (save for &amp;ldquo;A Song of Ice and Fire series&amp;rdquo; due to Game of Thrones&amp;rsquo; penultimate season) and couldn&#39;t recommend it higher.
Summary Chapter 1: High-Tech Marketing Illusion  In academic terms, such change sensitive products are called &amp;ldquo;discontinuous&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;disruptive innovations&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Made to Stick</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/books/made-to-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 12:52:46 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/books/made-to-stick/</guid>
      <description>An absolutely brilliant book detailing the six major qualities of a sticky idea: Simplicity, Unexpectedness, Concreteness, Credibility, Emetional, Stories. The Heath brothers investigate each of these six qualities in detail, investigating good and bad examples and paring their findings with academic studies. Not quite as academic as Predictably Irrational but a lot of the same themes show up.
Summary Chapter 1: Simple  Stick to the prime objective Southwest airlines is THE low-fare airline  Answers questions all the way down the org chart   Burying the lead  News should start with most important info and then decrease in importance down the page Burying the lead happens when most important points slip down the page   If you say 3 things, you don&#39;t say anything  Bill Clinton (1992) campaign must have one platform &amp;ldquo;It&#39;s the economy, stupid!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictably Irrational</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/books/predictably-irrational/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 09:26:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/books/predictably-irrational/</guid>
      <description>Overall a fantastic book detailing human behavior from a psychological and economic point of view. My favorite chapter was Cost of Social Norms, as it opened my eyes to a new point of view on interactions in a professional context. Dan Ariely does an amazing job detailing caveats of human irrationality throughout the book and I would say a must read for anyone.
Summary Chapter 1: The Truth About Relativity  Objectivity is nearly impossible  how much is something actually worth?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: Circle of Control</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/circle-of-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 16:48:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/circle-of-control/</guid>
      <description>After falling behind doing one of these a day by about a week and doing a lot of reflection in a single day, I&#39;m noticing a ton of repetition. In fact, circle of control was something that I reflected on here, here, here, and here. Not that this doesn&#39;t bear repeating, but circle of choice has started to sound like the circle of dead horses.
The author brings up a new point today though about how a stoic only controls his mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: The One Path to Serenity</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/one-path-to-serenity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 16:25:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/one-path-to-serenity/</guid>
      <description>Or Serenity Now!
If we trust all of the teachings up until today, the stoics leave us with the sound conclusion that the optimal way forward follows from us giving up everything outside of sphere of choice. Allowing ourselves to trust that fate or luck or God controls all else.
I struggle with this conclusion, not because I disagree with it but because it disagrees with my unrelenting existentialism. My sphere of influence never feels like a discrete function but a continuum that decays asymptotically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: If You Want to be Unsteady</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/if-you-want-to-be-unsteady/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 14:55:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/if-you-want-to-be-unsteady/</guid>
      <description>Similar to yesterday&#39;s meditation If You Want to be Steady today&#39;s explores the other side of the equation, analyzing the outcome of one focusing on things we cannot control. The unsteady, shaky nature we face when we only consider the outcomes out of our control as opposed to our judgment of those outcomes.
I&#39;m reminded of 2008 when a lot of my friends gambled professionally playing online poker. They would consistently play marathon sessions of heads-up poker online with 12 or more tables open at once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: If You Want to be Steady</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/if-you-want-to-be-steady/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 12:15:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/if-you-want-to-be-steady/</guid>
      <description>Epictetus waxes on judgement, questioning what drives us to make good choices versus bad ones. If we derive our decisions from external inputs, raw materials, how can we arrive at good or bad decisions if not for our judgments. If those we have skewed judgment of these externals, our actions could be bad.
This process reminds me of the flux pattern because it feels the stoics want to have a unidirectional flow of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: What We Control and What We Don&#39;t</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/what-we-control-what-we-dont/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 11:45:07 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/what-we-control-what-we-dont/</guid>
      <description>Epictetus has us reflect on what we control in our lives and what we don&#39;t. We control opinion, choice, desire, aversion, and anything of our own doing. We don&#39;t control our body, property, position, and everything outside of our control. However, and this is crucial, our response to things outside of our control remains within our control.
I refer to the human response to events outside our control as luck (some people see this same concept as karma, some see it as the hand of god.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: Seeing Our Addicitions</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/seeing-our-addictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 18:44:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/seeing-our-addictions/</guid>
      <description>Today, Seneca brings up the concept of addiction. Addiction affects many more people than we think it does. Everything from coffee to email to sex to video games put their hooks in to us and slowly chip away at our good intentions. Realizing an addiction becomes the first step toward improving, and sometimes this can be the hardest step.
The first step in AA is admitting you have a problem. In catholicism admitting a sin is the first step toward saving one&#39;s soul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: Seven Clear Functions of the Mind</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/seven-clear-functions-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 22:33:25 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/seven-clear-functions-mind/</guid>
      <description>Epictetus this time tells us that there are seven clear functions of mind: choice, refusal, yearning, repulsion, preparation, purpose, and assent. He concludes that only corrupt decisions made by a mind can pollute or clog its own function.
Thus far in January I&#39;ve reflected pretty hard on choice, refusal, purpose, and assent. So far those have been the guiding principles of my reflections in the new year, so it may behoove me to reflect on the other three today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: Where, Who, What and Why</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/where-who-what-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 11:32:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/where-who-what-why/</guid>
      <description>Marcus Aurelius today questions whether one can know where they are without understanding the universe, who they are without understanding their purpose in life, and without either of those why they are.
In Taoism, which I know little about, they have a term referred to as the uncarved block. The base existence without any exterior forces acting on one. A meditiation more than an ideal, if I understand correctly. Winnie the Pooh, arguably the strongest Taoist in child literature (The Tao of Pooh remains one of my favorite reads in my adolescence, although I probably need a refresher) simply flows with the wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: Clarify Your Intentions</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/clarify-your-intentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 22:28:32 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/clarify-your-intentions/</guid>
      <description>Clarifying my intentions to myself has been one of the strongest changes I&#39;ve made over the past few years. I can&#39;t say that in every stage and step of life I knew what my end goals are, but I&#39;m getting closer.
The big question people like to ask is &amp;ldquo;where do you see yourself in 5 (or 10 or 15) years?&amp;rdquo; My answer five years ago, like most people in their mid-twenties, was probably lacklackluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: The Big Three</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/the-big-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 21:51:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/the-big-three/</guid>
      <description>Control your perceptions, Direct your actions properly, Willingly accept what&#39;s outside your control.
Perception, action, and will are the big three. Clearly with these three statements aligned huge improvements are guaranteed.
For me the furthest from optimal is my ability to control my perceptions. When I feel things going the wrong way for me, my first reaction is people are acting subversively. For instance, when scheduling an appointment with someone&#39;s assistant, I constantly second guess any questions they ask or changes they make.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: Be Ruthless to the Things That Don&#39;t Matter</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/be-ruthless-to-things-that-dont-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 20:15:42 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/be-ruthless-to-things-that-dont-matter/</guid>
      <description>Today I reflect on saying no. No to new obligations, to invitations, and to exasperation (through saying no to undesired emotions.) Being able to say no, Seneca reasons, allows us to live more of our life the way we desire to live it.
I can&#39;t recall the first time I learned about the virtues of saying no. I do remember in 2012 answering a job interview question with the virtues of saying no.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: Education is Freedom</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/education-is-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 14:03:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/education-is-freedom/</guid>
      <description>Epictetus states that only the educated are free. That it’s not enough to say only the free should be educated. Cause and effect — cast off the shackles by learning.
Historically, learning has driven me. Not necessarily learning via an organized process, but understanding a concept down to the basics. Once I feel I understand, once I have forged my ring, I truly own that lesson. Freedom, in my view, is understanding and truly owning all of the lessons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: Control and Choice</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/control-and-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 14:01:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/control-and-choice/</guid>
      <description>Epictetus asks rhetorically where to do we look for good and evil? Within the externals that we have no control over or the choices that we control. Obviously things that we have no control over should not affect our happiness or outlook and yet so often we look at these externals as reflections of who we are, or some outcome of choices that we made. When we missed our connect flight by 2 minutes due to a delay I yelled my head off and acted really salty to the women at the gate, but it had no affect on the situation other than darkening my outlook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism January: Clarity</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/clarity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 13:55:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/2017/1/clarity/</guid>
      <description>The month’s focus is clarity. My initial reflections on clarity bring me back to an online RPG I played as a teenager called Everquest where in order to recover mana you had to just sit there. In fact, before you reached level 35 you had to sit there and stare at your spell book. The clarity spell cast by the enchanter class would speed up mana recovery significantly.
As I reflect more on the concept of clarity outside the realm of video games, I think of those fleeting glimpses of the world where all of my emotions express themselves in harmony.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism Meditations</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/background/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 12:58:15 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/daily-stoic/background/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve begun going through the 366 daily stoic meditations provided by (The Daily Stoic)[https://www.amazon.com/Daily-Stoic-Meditations-Wisdom-Perseverance/dp/0735211736]. I decided that there&#39;s no better way to distill my knowledge and share it with others than putting it in a daily update. I will likely falter and miss updating some days, but look forward to reading my musings on a few hundred meditations on Stoicism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World!</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:04:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve had &amp;ldquo;Make a personal website&amp;rdquo; on my todo list for about 5 years now. It always seemed daunting. At the end of the day, I continued to let the perfect be the enemy of the good and thus never pulled the trigger on it. But here we are, a reasonable website that&#39;s not great, but I&#39;m happy with the first step. As a goal for 2017, I plan to add my book reviews here, and attempt to write a blog post four times per month.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positioning: The Battle for Your Mind</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/books/positioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 18:10:04 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/posts/books/positioning/</guid>
      <description>Positioning is a short read from the 1980s that speaks to marketing in an overcommunicated society. Clearly more relevant today than ever, Al Ries addresses the phenomenon of being second to market in a competitive field. The case studies in the last 5 chapters help drive home the points. Strong introduction to market and product positioning. 7 / 10</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 16:06:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m a San Francisco Bay Area native. I grew up in Palo Alto, went to school at Stanford to study Computer Science and now live in SF.
By Day I&#39;m a problem solver. Usually this means working with others to build things using computers. I&#39;ve been a professional software engineer since 2007, a product manager since 2013, and an entrepreneur since 2014. I may be the most passionate person you&#39;ll ever work with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nothing here</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 16:06:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/tags/</guid>
      <description>Nothing here</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>