<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bookshelf on Compiling Leadership</title>
    <link>https://www.nedrockson.com/tags/bookshelf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bookshelf on Compiling Leadership</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019 Ned Rockson. Some Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 12:52:46 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.nedrockson.com/tags/bookshelf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Crossing the Chasm</title>
      <link>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/books/crossing-the-chasm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 12:52:46 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/books/crossing-the-chasm/</guid>
      <description>Absolutely fantastic book. I forgot to write a review for it initially and now (6 months later) I finally am getting back to it. I can say that over the past 6 months, this is the book I&amp;rsquo;ve referenced the most (save for &amp;ldquo;A Song of Ice and Fire series&amp;rdquo; due to Game of Thrones&amp;rsquo; penultimate season) and couldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend it higher.
Summary Chapter 1: High-Tech Marketing Illusion  In academic terms, such change sensitive products are called &amp;ldquo;discontinuous&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;disruptive innovations&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Made to Stick</title>
      <link>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/books/made-to-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 12:52:46 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/books/made-to-stick/</guid>
      <description>An absolutely brilliant book detailing the six major qualities of a sticky idea: Simplicity, Unexpectedness, Concreteness, Credibility, Emetional, Stories. The Heath brothers investigate each of these six qualities in detail, investigating good and bad examples and paring their findings with academic studies. Not quite as academic as Predictably Irrational but a lot of the same themes show up.
Summary Chapter 1: Simple  Stick to the prime objective Southwest airlines is THE low-fare airline  Answers questions all the way down the org chart   Burying the lead  News should start with most important info and then decrease in importance down the page Burying the lead happens when most important points slip down the page   If you say 3 things, you don&amp;rsquo;t say anything  Bill Clinton (1992) campaign must have one platform &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s the economy, stupid!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictably Irrational</title>
      <link>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/books/predictably-irrational/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 09:26:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/books/predictably-irrational/</guid>
      <description>Overall a fantastic book detailing human behavior from a psychological and economic point of view. My favorite chapter was Cost of Social Norms, as it opened my eyes to a new point of view on interactions in a professional context. Dan Ariely does an amazing job detailing caveats of human irrationality throughout the book and I would say a must read for anyone.
Summary Chapter 1: The Truth About Relativity  Objectivity is nearly impossible  how much is something actually worth?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positioning: The Battle for Your Mind</title>
      <link>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/books/positioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 18:10:04 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/books/positioning/</guid>
      <description>Positioning is a short read from the 1980s that speaks to marketing in an overcommunicated society. Clearly more relevant today than ever, Al Ries addresses the phenomenon of being second to market in a competitive field. The case studies in the last 5 chapters help drive home the points. Strong introduction to market and product positioning. 7 / 10</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>