<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>engineering on Compiling Leadership</title>
    <link>https://www.nedrockson.com/tags/engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in engineering on Compiling Leadership</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019 Ned Rockson. Some Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 20:01:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.nedrockson.com/tags/engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing consts and switch statements with go/ast</title>
      <link>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/engineering/testing-with-go-ast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 20:01:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/engineering/testing-with-go-ast/</guid>
      <description>(If you just want to look at the code, check it out on my github. Leave a comment if you want to chat about it!)
I believe that services in golang should abstract errors between their internal package and their api package. I find this makes managing errors and logic flows much more manageable, with one exception. There needs to exist a layer to convert an internal error into its API representation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview Correctly: Are You Selecting for the Right Things?</title>
      <link>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/management/interview-correctly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 21:24:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/management/interview-correctly/</guid>
      <description>I have been lucky to have interview training from small companies, large companies, and external consultants. I&amp;rsquo;ve practiced my skills while conducting at least 750 interviews over my career. I&amp;rsquo;d go so far as to call myself a well-trained interviewer.
In case you&amp;rsquo;ve never been part of a technical interview, I&amp;rsquo;ll give you a quick rundown. The candidate&amp;rsquo;s interview usually lasts between three to eight hours, with each interview taking between 30 minutes and one hour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Career Growth: Going Forward by Going Backward</title>
      <link>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/engineering/career-growth-going-forward-going-backward/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 17:09:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/engineering/career-growth-going-forward-going-backward/</guid>
      <description>One year ago I made a major career change. I transitioned from an engineering director position managing a team of 18 engineers and three managers to an individual contributor senior engineer.
Honestly, I struggled initially while deciding on the transition. It felt like my career would backslide with the change. On one hand, I had fought hard and succeeded to reach the director level and I enjoyed my team - in fact, I had hired almost half of them myself.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>