<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>management on Compiling Leadership</title>
    <link>https://www.nedrockson.com/tags/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in management on Compiling Leadership</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2019 Ned Rockson. Some Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 15:12:50 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.nedrockson.com/tags/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling by Giving Up Control</title>
      <link>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/management/scaling-by-giving-up-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 15:12:50 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/management/scaling-by-giving-up-control/</guid>
      <description>Every great engineer turned manager discovers she’s donned a set of bulky but powerful gloves. These gloves allow her to move much bigger rocks than before but hinder her ability to tinker with the fine details. She will struggle wearing these new gloves because until now she enjoyed and excelled at dealing with fine details. In order to succeed, the great engineer turned manager must remove herself from critical design and implementation paths.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Time Manager Mistakes: Don&#39;t Be Friends First</title>
      <link>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/management/dont-be-friends-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 15:37:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/management/dont-be-friends-first/</guid>
      <description>Evolution did a horrible job preparing me to manage in a workplace. Prior to 13,000 years ago with the introduction of agricultural societies, strong management skills were almost certainly selected against. Speaking loudly and carrying an even larger stick was in. Leading with vulnerability and subtly nudging people to improve undoubtedly led to short lifespans and few offspring. Leaders often were the biggest, strongest, and best with tools. During the following 13 millennia, countless leaders have proven that leadership no longer requires loud speech and proficiency with tools and weapons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Agile OR How to stop worrying and love self management</title>
      <link>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/management/early-agile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 20:41:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.nedrockson.com/posts/management/early-agile/</guid>
      <description>While researching the history of the standup meeting, I came across Jim Coplien&amp;rsquo;s 1994 retrospective on development of Borland Quattro Pro for Windows. In it, Jim analyzes a herculean effort where a team of eight developers wrote over 1 million lines of code over a 31 month period, or approximately 1,000 lines of code per week per developer1.
During development the team stumbled across early core agile principles almost a decade before the Agile Manifesto would be published.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>