<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily Stoic on Ned Rockson</title>
    <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/tags/daily-stoic/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Daily Stoic on Ned Rockson</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.nedrockson.com/tags/daily-stoic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: Circle of Control</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/circle-of-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 16:48:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/circle-of-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After falling behind doing one of these a day by about a week and doing a lot of reflection in a single day, I&amp;rsquo;m noticing a ton of repetition. In fact, circle of control was something that I reflected on &lt;a href=&#34;../control-and-choice/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;../if-you-want-to-be-steady/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;../if-you-want-to-be-unsteady/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;../what-we-control-what-we-dont/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Not that this doesn&amp;rsquo;t bear repeating, but circle of choice has started to sound like the circle of dead horses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author brings up a new point today though about how a stoic only controls his mind. His body even lives outside of his control. A calming conclusion for existential dread around singularity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: The One Path to Serenity</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/one-path-to-serenity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 16:25:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/one-path-to-serenity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Or Serenity Now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we trust all of the teachings up until today, the stoics leave us with the sound conclusion that the optimal way forward follows from us giving up everything outside of sphere of choice. Allowing ourselves to trust that fate or luck or God controls all else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I struggle with this conclusion, not because I disagree with it but because it disagrees with my unrelenting existentialism. My sphere of influence never feels like a discrete function but a continuum that decays asymptotically. This belief structure allows me to tackle obstacles that might appear as immovable (not to say I view myself as a super hero, but it amazes me sometimes what I can accomplish when I question everything.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, today I looked at my credit card bill and found Google charged me $400 for a Google Cloud Platform account I closed almost a year ago. Until now Google had charged me $400 per month without my knowledge because I still had credits on my account covering the balance. Now that they expired, I found out that my account while closed for all intents and purposes still had a recurring charge on it. Frustrated, I have now begun the process of talking with support to cancel my account first and foremost, but secondly to try and get my money back, because I believe Google charged me in error. While aggrevating, I feel lucky that I checked my credit card statement closely this month instead of in March. I saved myself some future loss!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My approach may not follow the guidelines of a stoic, but how would a Stoic react in this case? If Epictetus lived today and saw this errant charge, how would he act and feel?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe mentally, he would resign himself to having lost the money. His made choices in the past that he cannot override. While he could have made choices more optimally in the past, he cannot change something in the past. This decision does not reside in his sphere of choice or control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His actions may be the same - to immediately address the problem with whatever support he may encounter. He may ask for a refund as this clearly was not intended by him and Google does not practice predatory billing practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major difference between Epictetus&amp;rsquo; outcome and my own is I let this weigh on me. I let it affect my affect. As I continue my journey I hope these events will not have such a strong affect on me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: If You Want to be Unsteady</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/if-you-want-to-be-unsteady/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 14:55:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/if-you-want-to-be-unsteady/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Similar to yesterday&amp;rsquo;s meditation &lt;a href=&#34;../if-you-want-to-be-steady/&#34;&gt;If You Want to be Steady&lt;/a&gt; today&amp;rsquo;s explores the other side of the equation, analyzing the outcome of one focusing on things we cannot control. The unsteady, shaky nature we face when we only consider the outcomes out of our control as opposed to our judgment of those outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m reminded of 2008 when a lot of my friends gambled professionally playing online poker. They would consistently play marathon sessions of heads-up poker online with 12 or more tables open at once. I marvelled at their abilities as one might to a chessmaster&amp;rsquo;s epic ability to take on multiple opponents simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I found their ability to handle large swings in finances even more amazing. The variance they handled in a given week could range anywhere from losing $50,000 to winning $50,000 (and probably distributed normally within that range.) One bad day I watched my friend lose $10,000 and play it off simply as part of the job. Imagining events beyond my control dictating my life, and more importantly my ability to pay rent or eat showed me this life would never work for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did my friends possess some powerful stoic motives that I lacked? Possibly, however their heroic intake of drugs and alcohol likely helped them deal with the unpredictable nature of their professions. Do they have a larger tolerance for stochastic outcomes? Almost definitely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I take a bad beat in poker I try very hard to not get caught up on the bad luck. Clearly, drawing a four outer will not happen every time, but it can feel like it. I try to focus on my play and whether I did everything in my control to succeed. Even if I played my hand exactly right and just ended up on the wrong side of the probability curve, I still find it hard to appreciate what I cannot control. My judgment gets away from me and I inherently become unsteady.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe avoiding unsteadiness happens through reflection but also aversion. Controlling my aversions puts not gambling for a living right near the top of the list. While I can dream of a day where I fully embody the stoic persona and could, potentially, take on a career of gambling I don&amp;rsquo;t believe it will be in the near future. I also hope when that day comes that my dreams do not involve gambling for a living.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: If You Want to be Steady</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/if-you-want-to-be-steady/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 12:15:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/if-you-want-to-be-steady/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Epictetus waxes on judgement, questioning what drives us to make good choices versus bad ones. If we derive our decisions from external inputs, raw materials, how can we arrive at good or bad decisions if not for our judgments. If those we have skewed judgment of these externals, our actions could be bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This process reminds me of the flux pattern because it feels the stoics want to have a unidirectional flow of data. In flux, inputs cause actions which influence reducers which update a store. The store updates the internal state of the system which the user sees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applied to the stoic&amp;rsquo;s life, the system sounds similar. Raw data (input) comes in to which a stoic applies judgment (reducers) to generate opinions (store) which manifest into actions (system state). If a bug exists within any of these stages, just like in a flux modeled computer system, the outcomes are skewed and may become unpredictable. Crashes occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within this analogy of a stoic&amp;rsquo;s life, being steady solely relates to having well tuned and tested reducers. Without these, external inputs will affect internal state differently than expected and cause inconsistent external actions from the Stoic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: What We Control and What We Don&#39;t</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/what-we-control-what-we-dont/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 11:45:07 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/what-we-control-what-we-dont/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Epictetus has us reflect on what we control in our lives and what we don&amp;rsquo;t. We control opinion, choice, desire, aversion, and anything of our own doing. We don&amp;rsquo;t control our body, property, position, and everything outside of our control. However, and this is crucial, our &lt;strong&gt;response&lt;/strong&gt; to things outside of our control remains within our control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I refer to the human response to events outside our control as luck (some people see this same concept as karma, some see it as the hand of god.) I believe I&amp;rsquo;ve reflected on luck before during these stoicism meditations, but it bears revisiting (and will likely stay on my mind for some time.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a person continually views himself as unlucky or cursed by god, he does not realize he can control his own luck. Consider Job, a biblical character who had nearly everything in his life go wrong. The story goes that Judeo Christian God tested him to see whether he praised God because of his protection and good fortune due to God (It actually turns out that Satan led to this testing &amp;ndash; I lack strong education in biblical studies. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Job_(biblical_figure)&#34;&gt;Good overview here&lt;/a&gt;. Job curses the day of his birth, but stops short of accusing or cursing God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I do not believe in an almighty power, I do believe in the power of religion to impart basic values. In the case of Job, we see that God (or luck) controlled him rather than the opposite. Instead of blaming this force, Job accepted that a reason existed for his misfortune. Furthermore, he lamented his existence, but not the existence of a cruel deity (or bad luck.) In the end, because the bible likes fables, God restores his happiness because he passed the test. (As a side note, it turns out Job appears in Old Testament (Judaism), New Testament (Christianity), and Qu&amp;rsquo;ran (Islam)).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strong parallels exist between Job and the idea of knowing what we control and what we don&amp;rsquo;t. If Job believed he controlled his property or position, nothing good would come of him. Had he not controlled his response to the events of losing his wealth, he would have ended up going insane. Instead, he bitterly accepted the events, never cursing God (his bad luck,) even though it clearly made him depressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bad things happen to all of us. People who can accept the events as outside of their control and find a way to stay positive, or at least rational, tend to have better outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve started down the road of making my own luck, I generally have been happier and have had a more steady outlook on life. When someone smashed my car window, I could have looked at it as a terrible event, but instead I saw the positive that in ten years of living in a city and parking on the street it happened once. Five years ago I would not have had such a bright outlook. I can say categorically my life has improved as I&amp;rsquo;ve begun to control my responses to events outside of my control.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: Seeing Our Addicitions</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/seeing-our-addictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 18:44:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/seeing-our-addictions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, Seneca brings up the concept of addiction. Addiction affects many more people than we think it does. Everything from coffee to email to sex to video games put their hooks in to us and slowly chip away at our good intentions. Realizing an addiction becomes the first step toward improving, and sometimes this can be the hardest step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step in AA is admitting you have a problem. In catholicism admitting a sin is the first step toward saving one&amp;rsquo;s soul. Without recognizing and admitting there is an issue, how can one be expected to fix it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first addiction was video games. I could spend more hours playing video games than doing all other things combined for weeks at a time. Video games could overcome me to the point that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make conversation without referring to them. I still recall going to a New Year&amp;rsquo;s party when I was 16 and realized I had nothing to talk about but the new weapon I had acquired in a video game. Beyond video games I&amp;rsquo;ve had, and still have, many addictions. Coffee and cigarettes are the two physical ones. I occasionally relapse with video games. I can quickly get wrapped up in a new hobby to where some might say I am becoming addicted as it pervades every part of my being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My addictive personality has taught me a lot about myself and addiction. It&amp;rsquo;s made me accept that addictions can show up anywhere, and for reasons that rarely follow logical pathways. Addictions for me generally appear as ways to cope with powerful thoughts and emotions. In college, I struggled with social anxiety and alcohol helped me cope with it. It helped me so much that I quickly required alcohol to have any type of social interaction. When even alcohol didn&amp;rsquo;t help, I could escape with video games. This created a fertile breeding ground for addiction because these behaviors helped me cope with something that was difficult. Once I established a pattern of behavior it became even more difficult to break out of it. If social interaction was tough before the behavior, it became even more difficult without the behavior was established.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, recognizing my addiction became the first step to improvement. I realized that I wasted countless hours inebriated or ignoring reality and I wanted to change. Recognizing that I had addictions to realize was the first step. The steps afterward were not easy, but once I saw them I was able to measure them and once I was able to measure them I could fix them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have addictions today I struggle with. Coffee is an addiction I&amp;rsquo;ll never say goodbye to because it&amp;rsquo;s too dang good and not bad enough for me to convince me to live without it. Smoking tabacco on the other hand is something I&amp;rsquo;d love to never do again. No matter how hard I try to kick that one, it hangs around. I see it. I recognize it. Now to stop it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: Seven Clear Functions of the Mind</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/seven-clear-functions-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 22:33:25 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/seven-clear-functions-mind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Epictetus this time tells us that there are seven clear functions of mind: choice, refusal, yearning, repulsion, preparation, purpose, and assent. He concludes that only corrupt decisions made by a mind can pollute or clog its own function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus far in January I&amp;rsquo;ve reflected pretty hard on choice, refusal, purpose, and assent. So far those have been the guiding principles of my reflections in the new year, so it may behoove me to reflect on the other three today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yearning sounds right at home in the stoic&amp;rsquo;s toolbox. I&amp;rsquo;ve yearned to be better so strongly that I&amp;rsquo;ve lost sight of all else. Yearning to become a cyclist, I did nothing in my free time but ride my bicycle. I read nothing but bicycling (non-fiction) books. I &lt;em&gt;lengthened&lt;/em&gt; my commute to spend more time on the bike in the mornings and evenings. I yearned so strongly that I lost all control of my desires to improve. Yearning in a vacuum may not produce sustainable results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repulsion of negativity and bad impulses is something I am getting stronger at, but still on a path toward truly mastering. While having a deep conversation this week, I offered up the viewpoint that my optimism has grown over the past decade so much that I might not recognize myself now. I can&amp;rsquo;t yet say that I repulse negativity, but I have grown, strongly, to fight off negative responses and exude positivity. The world feels like a better place, even if I sometimes feel like I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;ldquo;faking it before I make it&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Fortune (luck) favors the prepared&amp;rdquo; - Louis Pasteur. After becoming entranced with the thought that luck could be a trait, like in D&amp;amp;D, I arrived on this quote. It has rang out in my thoughts and speech for the past few months. It put to bed my opinions that some people are lucky and some just aren&amp;rsquo;t. Preparation is a way for one to build their own luck, and they can supplement it with optimism and general outlook on life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: Where, Who, What and Why</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/where-who-what-why/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 11:32:49 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/where-who-what-why/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Marcus Aurelius today questions whether one can know where they are without understanding the universe, who they are without understanding their purpose in life, and without either of those why they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Taoism, which I know little about, they have a term referred to as the uncarved block. The base existence without any exterior forces acting on one. A meditiation more than an ideal, if I understand correctly. Winnie the Pooh, arguably the strongest Taoist in child literature (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Tao-Pooh-Benjamin-Hoff/dp/0140067477&#34;&gt;The Tao of Pooh&lt;/a&gt; remains one of my favorite reads in my adolescence, although I probably need a refresher) simply flows with the wind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winnie the Pooh&amp;rsquo;s lack of understanding of the universe or who he was led to a different outcome that I would argue is the opposite of a Stoic, especially with regards to this Marcus Aurelius&amp;rsquo; excerpt. His approach to life was empirical. His approach to life was far stronger related to &lt;a href=&#34;../be-ruthless-to-things-that-dont-matter/&#34;&gt;Seneca&amp;rsquo;s excerpt on January 3&lt;/a&gt; because he let&amp;rsquo;s nothing out of his control bother him. In fact, if we follow that line of thought, it&amp;rsquo;s not unreasonable to peg Winnie the Pooh as a Stoic (although a Goole search for &lt;code&gt;Winnie the Pooh Stoicism&lt;/code&gt; is not reinforcing my claim. Making this argument will be my own task.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s is the first exercise that has made me strongly reflect on the writings, and not just because the author references Mitch Hedberg in his analysis. Aurelius puts it plain that without knowing about the universe and my purpose in life, I cannot know the basic truths about myself. This viewpoint scares me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to say that I understand the universe as it is relevant to me. I want to say that I know my purpose in life, as it&amp;rsquo;s relevant to me. However, these thoughts always make me think of the video &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0fKBhvDjuy0&#34;&gt;Powers of Ten&lt;/a&gt; I watched in 7th grade science class. It made me realize that no matter how confident my knowledge of a topic, zooming out or in on the context provides an order of magnitude more and my confidence could be shattered knowing that it&amp;rsquo;s only a fraction of what truly exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the enormity of the universe or our purpose in the universe, can anyone (especially me) have a concept of their purpose, or what the universe is? Are we doomed to not know who we are, where we are, why we are?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe it&amp;rsquo;s best to err on the side of Winnie the Pooh and understand the universe as that understanding is within our control. Same for our purpose in life. Otherwise we&amp;rsquo;re doomed to constantly face the spectre of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technology_in_The_Hitchhiker&#39;s_Guide_to_the_Galaxy#Total_Perspective_Vortex&#34;&gt;Total Perspective Vortex&lt;/a&gt; and all the stoicism in the universe wouldn&amp;rsquo;t help us then (unless, of course, you happen to be Zaphod Beeblebrox who looked at his insignificance as the utmost claim of his significance. I guess Trump could have the same misconception&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: Clarify Your Intentions</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/clarify-your-intentions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 22:28:32 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/clarify-your-intentions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Clarifying my intentions to myself has been one of the strongest changes I&amp;rsquo;ve made over the past few years. I can&amp;rsquo;t say that in every stage and step of life I knew what my end goals are, but I&amp;rsquo;m getting closer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big question people like to ask is &amp;ldquo;where do you see yourself in 5 (or 10 or 15) years?&amp;rdquo; My answer five years ago, like most people in their mid-twenties, was probably lacklackluster. I doubt I&amp;rsquo;d have predicted that in five years I&amp;rsquo;d have started a few companies, improved my professional confidence, have a beautiful girlfriend who I plan on marrying, and a stronger understanding of myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I try really hard to remember what I wanted when I was 27, I remember wanting to have a stronger personal life, to have a fulfilling romantic relationship, to win more (where winning wasn&amp;rsquo;t well defined,) and to enjoy my professional life more. I can say with great confidence that I achieved all of those goals, but not because I was striving to those ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I can say that I&amp;rsquo;m very happy with where I am, but going through lots of change where I don&amp;rsquo;t have clear intentions. This day&amp;rsquo;s meditations have made me realize that I need a good framework for what my intentions and goals are. This will guide my actions, help me know if I&amp;rsquo;m on the right track, and let me know when I&amp;rsquo;ve finished.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: The Big Three</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/the-big-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 21:51:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/the-big-three/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Control your perceptions,
Direct your actions properly,
Willingly accept what&amp;rsquo;s outside your control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perception, action, and will are the big three. Clearly with these three statements aligned huge improvements are guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me the furthest from optimal is my ability to control my perceptions. When I feel things going the wrong way for me, my first reaction is people are acting subversively. For instance, when scheduling an appointment with someone&amp;rsquo;s assistant, I constantly second guess any questions they ask or changes they make. I &lt;em&gt;perceive&lt;/em&gt; the person I&amp;rsquo;m trying to schedule with filtering their shade through the pen of their assistant, when in reality, I&amp;rsquo;m competing against many for a few slots on a calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Controlling perception comes down to giving full focus to my emotions. So much of what I perceive gets filtered through knee jerk reactions that if I find a way to slow down and actually analyze the emotions that my perceptions will feel more controlled. Perhaps not correct, but controlled.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: Be Ruthless to the Things That Don&#39;t Matter</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/be-ruthless-to-things-that-dont-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 20:15:42 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/be-ruthless-to-things-that-dont-matter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I reflect on saying no. No to new obligations, to invitations, and to exasperation (through saying no to undesired emotions.) Being able to say no, Seneca reasons, allows us to live more of our life the way we desire to live it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t recall the first time I learned about the virtues of saying no. I do remember in 2012 answering a job interview question with the virtues of saying no. I suppose I had become so overworked at a prior job that I learned (either through a great teacher or osmosis, I can&amp;rsquo;t remember) that saying no to projects, responsibilities, and social engagements was necessary to maintain my sanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; strong introvert who likes people, I used to wrestle with social invitations. On the one hand, I knew I will enjoy a party but on the other my energy levels are finite and I needed to choose where I spend my social energy. This struggle in college, before I learned how to say no effectively, led to a bimodal existence. I was either socializing and living it up or completely zapped and sleeping 12 or more hours a day to regain my energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today saying no walks a less fine line. Unless I feel very confident that the opportunity presented to me definitely appeals to me then I try to say no. My resolve wavers periodically, but most of the time I am better for it when I stick to my guns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: Education is Freedom</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/education-is-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 14:03:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/education-is-freedom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Epictetus states that only the educated are free. That it’s not enough to say only the free should be educated. Cause and effect — cast off the shackles by learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically, learning has driven me. Not necessarily learning via an organized process, but understanding a concept down to the basics. Once I feel I understand, once I have &lt;a href=&#34;http://awoiaf.westeros.org/index.php/Maesters#Collar&#34;&gt;forged my ring&lt;/a&gt;, I truly own that lesson. Freedom, in my view, is understanding and truly owning all of the lessons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author reminds us to remember that learning grants freedom on the days when we feel distracted. On the days where we choose to waste time instead of read or learn, to remember that it is not what we have learned that allows us freedom but the act of continual study that grants it to us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism: Control and Choice</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/control-and-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 14:01:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/control-and-choice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Epictetus asks rhetorically where to do we look for good and evil? Within the externals that we have no control over or the choices that we control. Obviously things that we have no control over should not affect our happiness or outlook and yet so often we look at these externals as reflections of who we are, or some outcome of choices that we made. When we missed our connect flight by 2 minutes due to a delay I yelled my head off and acted really salty to the women at the gate, but it had no affect on the situation other than darkening my outlook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AA uses the serenity prayer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;God, grant me the serenity to accept the things I cannot change,
Courage to change the things I can,
And wisdom to know the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I am not an alcoholic, nor in AA, nor believe in god, the premise is spot on. In fact, knowing the difference is the first part I will tackle. It’s so easy to get wrapped up in things that I cannot control that in a lot of cases I can’t discern what I can’t control vs what I can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism January: Clarity</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/clarity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 13:55:40 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/2017/1/clarity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The month’s focus is clarity. My initial reflections on clarity bring me back to an online RPG I played as a teenager called &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/EverQuest&#34;&gt;Everquest&lt;/a&gt; where in order to recover mana you had to just sit there. In fact, before you reached level 35 you had to sit there and stare at your spell book. The clarity spell cast by the enchanter class would speed up mana recovery significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I reflect more on the concept of clarity outside the realm of video games, I think of those fleeting glimpses of the world where all of my emotions express themselves in harmony. Suddenly everything becomes clear and my correct and optimal path shows itself. A brief moment of clarity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clarity in the engineering world has been far simpler to achieve. The path of implementation for a new product, concept, or test discovers me a lot of the time. Even when there’s a problem that does not lend an easy solution, I can see how to tackle it by breaking it down into components or sub problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to going through this month, I think that clarity is like being in the zone. When I&amp;rsquo;m there, things move more slowly so I can solve problems quicker. When I’m there I can feel every muscle in my body working for me. When I’m there I understand things without needing to focus on them. When I’m there, things seem to happen effortlessly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I go into this month with my eyes open and ready to meditate on thirty one concepts around clarity. New year, new goals and I look forward to learning and sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Stoicism Meditations</title>
      <link>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/background/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 12:58:15 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.nedrockson.com/post/daily-stoic/background/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve begun going through the 366 daily stoic meditations provided by (The Daily Stoic)[&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Daily-Stoic-Meditations-Wisdom-Perseverance/dp/0735211736&#34;&gt;https://www.amazon.com/Daily-Stoic-Meditations-Wisdom-Perseverance/dp/0735211736&lt;/a&gt;]. I decided that there&amp;rsquo;s no better way to distill my knowledge and share it with others than putting it in a daily update. I will likely falter and miss updating some days, but look forward to reading my musings on a few hundred meditations on Stoicism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>